Guide to the Thornton Wilder Papers
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
- Photographs, 1900-1972; Series V; 2.71; (7 boxes)
  - PHOTOGRAPHS OF OTHERS
    - Gielgud, John, Sir, inscribed to Isabel Wilder, 1962 (Box 153, Folder 3685)
    - Gish, Lillian and Wilder, inscribed by Gish to Wilder, 1957 (Box 153, Folder 3686)
    - Glenn, C. Leslie, n.d. (Box 153, Folder 3687)
    - Goodbody, Doug and family, 1969 Oct (Box 153, Folder 3688)
    - Greene, Shirley and Harold, TW exhibit Pan American College, Edinburg, TX, 1967 Apr (Box 153, Folder 3689)
    - Guelf, Fruella, n.d. (Box 153, Folder 3690)
    - Guthrie, ---, 1962 (Box 153, Folder 3691)
    - Heyck family, 1965 Dec (Box 153, Folder 3692)
    - Hindemith, Gertrude at the Hindemith Commemoration (Box 153, Folder 3693)
    - Kazan, Elia and family (Box 153, Folder 3694)
    - Klose, Gertrude and family (Box 153, Folder 3695)
    - Legrand, Julian and Roland, 1964 (Box 153, Folder 3696)
    - Lille, Ralph, n.d. (Box 153, Folder 3697)
    - Luhan, Mabel Dodge, 1964 (Box 153, Folder 3698)
    - Mancatis, Georgia, n.d. (Box 153, Folder 3699)
    - Martin, Mary and entourage: strip proofs (Box 153, Folder 3700)
    - Merken, Frances, inscribed to Wilder, 1931 Aug 25 (Box 153, Folder 3701)
    - Merlin, Elsa, inscribed to Wilder, n.d. (Box 153, Folder 3702)
    - Niven, Isabel, [1893?]
    - O'Neil, F. J., n.d. (Box 153, Folder 3703)
    - Oxford Summer School student portrait, 1927
    - Peterboro, Mary, 1932 (Box 153, Folder 3704)
    - [Reinhardt, Helene?], n.d. (Box 153, Folder 3705)
    - Sahl, Hans family, n.d. (Box 153, Folder 3706)
    - Schweitzer, Albert and Preminger, Marion, 1954-56, n.d. (Box 153, Folder 3707-3708)
      Some photographs annotated by Preminger and inscribed to Wilder
    - Senn, Fritz and family, 1961 (Box 153, Folder 3709)
    - Stein, Gertrude with Alice B. Toklas and Dorothy Ulrich, [1938 Sep 23] (Box 153, Folder 3710)
      Inscribed: "Dorothy Ulrich visits the ladies of Bilignin"
    - Trego, Nina, n.d. (Box 153, Folder 3711)
    - Tritschler, Anita, n.d. (Box 153, Folder 3712)
    - Tunney, Gene, [1926?]-28, n.d. (Box 153, Folder 3713)
      One undated picture includes Thornton Wilder
      See also: Oversize, Box 166, folder 3964
    - Wilder, Charlotte, n.d. (Box 153, Folder 3714)
    - Wilder, Isabel, [1930s]
    - Wilder, Isabel, [ca. 1950] (Box 153, Folder 3715)
    - Wilder, Isabel with Janet Dakin, Toby Dakin, Amos Wilder, New Haven, 1969 Aug (Box 153, Folder 3716)
    - Wilder, Isabel, marked "To Thorny 1974" (Box 153, Folder 3717)
    - Worth, Irene, 1950-68, n.d. (Box 153, Folder 3718)
    - Chaguin Falls High School graduation, 1964 Jun (Box 153, Folder 3719)
    - Unidentified school group birthday party for TN, 1967 (Box 153, Folder 3720)
    - Unidentified, n.d. (Box 153, Folder 3721)
    - Unidentified artist posing with works, inscribed to Wilder, n.d.
  - PRODUCTIONS OF PLAYS BY WILDER
    - Alcestiade
      - Photographs of the German production, n.d. (Box 154, Folder 3722-3723)
    - "The Happy Journey to Trenton and Camden"
      - Antioch Players production, 1931 Dec 11 (Box 154, Folder 3724)
    - "The Long Christmas Dinner"
      - Unidentified production, n.d. (Box 154, Folder 3725)
    - Lucrece
      - Provincetown Players production, 1964 (Box 154, Folder 3726)
    - The Matchmaker
      - Czech production, n.d. (Box 154, Folder 3727-3731)
      - Finnish production, [1950s?] (Box 154, Folder 3732)
      - Greek production, [1960s?] (Box 154, Folder 3733)
      - Uruguayan production, n.d. (Box 154, Folder 3734)
    - The Merchant of Yonkers
      - "Ohio Wesleyan University, Fall 1941" (Box 154, Folder 3735)
    - Our Town
      - Wilder in Our Town, New York production, 1938 (Box 154, Folder 3736)
      - Ohio Wesleyan University production, 1939 (Box 154, Folder 3737)
      - Cape Playhouse production, 1939 (Box 154, Folder 3738-3741)
      - Hong Kong production of Rod Serling, [1950s?] (Box 154, Folder 3742-3745)
      - Wilder in production at Williamstown Summer Theatre: album, 1959
      - Danish production, [1970?] (Box 154, Folder 3746)
      - Hungarian production, [1964?] (Box 154, Folder 3747-3749)
        See also: Oversize, Box 170, folder 3970
      - Unidentified productions, n.d. (Box 154, Folder 3750-3752)
    - Plays for Bleeker Street
      - Pacific University Theatre production, n.d. (Box 154, Folder 3753)
    - "Pullman Car Hiawatha"
      - Unidentified production, n.d. (Box 154, Folder 3754)
    - "Seven Ages of Man: Infancy"
      - Italian production, n.d. (Box 154, Folder 3755)
    - "Seven Ages of Man: Childhood"
      - Italian production, 1962-63 (Box 154, Folder 3756)
    - "Seven Deadly Sins: Lust"
      - Italian production, n.d. (Box 154, Folder 3757)
    - The Skin of Our Teeth
      - Plymouth Theatre production, 1943
      - Manchester Opera House production, 1949
      - Westport production with Wilder in cast, 1948 (Box 155, Folder 3758)
        See also: Oversize, Box 164, folder 3944
      - Pittsfield production with Wilder in cast, [1951?] (Box 155, Folder 3759)
      - Berea College production, 1955 (Box 155, Folder 3760)
      - Theatre Sarah Bernhardt production, 1955
      - University of Oregon production, [1950s] (Box 155, Folder 3761)
      - London production, [1950s] (Box 155, Folder 3762-3766)
      - Polish production: album, 1957
        Includes programs, reviews, clippings. Inscribed to Wilder by the Polish ambassador, 1957 Mar 7
      - Virginia Museum production, 1960 (Box 155, Folder 3767)
      - Guthrie Theatre production, 1966 (Box 155, Folder 3768)
      - German production, [1960s] (Box 155, Folder 3769)
      - [Milwaukee?] production, 1971 (Box 155, Folder 3770)
      - Television production, 1972 (Box 155, Folder 3771)
      - Unidentified productions, n.d. (Box 155, Folder 3772-3775)
  - OBJECTS
    - Ceramic dish by Picasso, n.d. (Box 155, Folder 3776)
    - Coatrack at Deepwood Drive, n.d. (Box 155, Folder 3777)
    - Collage titled "Skin of Our Teeth", 1961 (Box 155, Folder 3778)
    - National Medal for Literature, 1965 (Box 155, Folder 3779)
    - Page of manuscript of The Woman of Andros (with negative) (Box 155, Folder 3780)
    - Portraits of Wilder, 1949 (Box 155, Folder 3781-3782)
      Includes photograph of portrait bust by Archipenko, signed by Archipenko
      See also: Oversize, Box 164, folder 3937 and folder 3943
  - HOUSES
    - 150 Holland Park Ave., ca. 1900 (Box 155, Folder 3783)
    - "First Berkeley house", 1906 (Box 155, Folder 3784)
    - 2675 Parker Street
    - "Wilder house, Berkeley-- 1906-1908 1/2", n.d. (Box 155, Folder 3785)
    - "Shanghai house", 1911-12 (Box 155, Folder 3786-3787)
    - Pomona, California, 1912 (Box 155, Folder 3788)
    - David House, Lawrenceville, 1922 (Box 155, Folder 3789)
    - Deepwood Drive house, 1935, n.d. (Box 155, Folder 3790)
    - Deepwood Drive interior, n.d. (Box 155, Folder 3791)
    - "View from Thornton Wilder's room, Princeton Graduate College", n.d. (Box 155, Folder 3792)
    - "A bridge in Frog Hollow and the Princeton Graduate College" (Box 155, Folder 3793)
    - Kabama House, Edgarton, 1980 Jul (Box 155, Folder 3794)
    - Maple Bluff, n.d. (Box 155, Folder 3795)
    - "Forest Path" by John L. de Forest, n.d.
    - Miscellaneous/unidentified, n.d. (Box 155, Folder 3796)
      Includes photograph annotated by Isabel Wilder: "The 'Dump.' Wellfleet, Mass. July 1953. Taken by Roddy McDowall." Later annotation also by IW: "(Monty Clift)".
- Memorabilia and Other Papers, 1923-1963; Series VI; 1.05; (3 boxes)
  Series VI, Memorabilia and Other Papers, is arranged alphabetically by type of material.
  - Advertisements and tickets (Box 156, Folder 3797-3800)
  - Appointment calendar inscribed and annotated by Marion Preminger, 1946 (Box 156, Folder 3800a)
  - Artwork
    - Abercrombie, Gertrude: oil portrait of TW, n.d.
    - Beerbohm, Max: drawing of Henry James, 1949 Jan (Box 156, Folder 3801)
    - Enters, Angna: drawings and watercolors, 1953-63 (Box 156, Folder 3802-3805)
    - "E.W.F.": flower paintings on cardboard, n.d. (Box 156, Folder 3806-3809)
    - Lawrence, William: death mask of TW, n.d.
    - Leighton, Claire: "The Angel on the Ship," lithograph, 1930 (Box 156, Folder 3810)
    - Metz, Reinhold: Drawings inscribed to TW, 1973, n.d.
    - Noguchi, Isamu
      - Portrait head of TW, in bronze, n.d.
    - Pratt, John: "Life Among the Angels," volume of pen and wash drawings, 1934
      Inscribed: "Thornton Wilder from John Pratt. Park Ridge. January 24, 1934."
    - [Rust, Rosalind?]: caricature of group listening to Wilder play harp, pencil and colored wash (Box 156, Folder 3811)
    - Photograph of unidentified portrait of a woman, n.d.
    - Print of 18th century? scene [Palazzo Reale, Caserta, Italy], 2 copies, n.d.
  - Autographs
    - Arnat, Don Manuel de: signature on autograph document, 1767 Jul 28 (Box 156, Folder 3812)
      With: envelope annotated by Wilder, "Signature of Viceroy of Peru"
    - Bernhardt, Sarah, 1905 Dec 29 (Box 156, Folder 3813)
    - Dardos y Lisson, Pedro: inscription to Thornton Wilder on title page of "Bolivar", 1941 (Box 156, Folder 3814)
  - Background Book: International Conference of Artists, Venice, Italy, 1952 Sep (Box 156, Folder 3815)
  - Bible inscription: front pages of Bible inscribed "Thornton Niven Wilder, Shanghai, China, Dec. 11, 1911" (Box 156, Folder 3816)
  - Bookplates, n.d. (Box 156, Folder 3817)
  - Book jacket and book cover, unidentified fragments (Box 156, Folder 3818)
  - Bookdealers' catalogs, n.d. (Box 156, Folder 3819)
  - Cartoon of Thornton Wilder receiving inspiration [from "Ripley's Believe It or Not"], n.d. (Box 156, Folder 3820)
  - Conference programs, 1963-65 (Box 156, Folder 3821)
  - Copyright information, 1971-81, n.d. (Box 156, Folder 3822)
    Includes article by Stanley Rothenberg on motion picture copyright issues
  - Directories: Lawrenceville School, 1923-28 (Box 156, Folder 3823-3825)
  - Directories: University of Chicago, 1931-33 (Box 156, Folder 3826-3827)
  - Directories: University of Chicago, 1934-36 (Box 157, Folder 3828-3829)
  - Fabric folder: gift of Louise Talma, n.d. (Box 157, Folder 3830)
  - Lecture brochures, 1933-57 (Box 157, Folder 3831)
  - Menu, 1928 Jul 19 (Box 157, Folder 3832)
  - Menu and invitation for a dinner in honor of Prince Bernhard of the Netherlands, 1967 Sep 25
  - Music by Louise Talma
    - "Bagatelles for Thornton," holograph score, 1955
    - "Birthday Song for Thornton, April 17, 1960," holograph score, signed
    - "Etude," holograph score, signed, 1954
      Dedication: "For Thornton, the originator....1954 Feb 3."
    - "Passacaglia and Fugue," holograph score, signed, 1962
      Dedication: "For Thornton: Ricordo di Roma e di Francoforte"
    - "Pastoral Prelude: for Rick," printed, 1949 (Box 157, Folder 3832a)
    - "Piano Sonata No. 2," holograph score, 1955 Aug 22
      Dedication: "To Thornton Wilder."
    - "Sonata," published scores, 1962
      Copy 2 carries the dedication "In homage to Nadia Boulanger on her seventy-fifth birthday, September 16, 1962."
    - Unidentified fragments, n.d.
  - Music by Others
    - Program for a concert aboard the "S.S. Adriatic" featuring Wilder, 1928 Jul 13 (Box 157, Folder 3833)
    - Edmunds, John: "Carol: The Angel Game," manuscript score, 1953 Sep 21 (Box 157, Folder 3833a)
      Inscribed: "for Thornton Wilder with much love and devotion... MacDowell Colony, 21 Sept. 1953."
    - "Encantadora Maria": manuscript in the hand of TW
    - "The Washington Square Boarding House: a Suite for Three Bad Violins": manuscript in the hand of TW (Box 157, Folder 3834)
    - Score of Handel's Xerxes, in German, printed, incomplete (Box 157, Folder 3834a)
      Annotated by TW
    - Unidentified song music, n.d. (Box 157, Folder 3835)
  - National Institute of Arts and Letters, 1941 (Box 157, Folder 3836)
  - Notes on South American Writers, [1941?] (Box 157, Folder 3837)
  - Questionnaire concerning Max Reinhardt, typescript copy, [1964] (Box 157, Folder 3838)
  - Perpetual calendar (Box 157, Folder 3839)
  - Plan for the Pan-American Institute, n.d. (Box 157, Folder 3840)
  - Postcards, blank, n.d. (Box 157, Folder 3841)
  - "The Problem of Population and Aging," typescript photocopy (Box 157, Folder 3842)
  - Stationery, n.d. (Box 157, Folder 3843)
  - Who's Who in America materials, n.d. (Box 157, Folder 3844)
- Audiotapes and Other Recordings, 1949-1967; Series VII; 1.25; (4 boxes)
  Series VII, Audio Tapes and Other Recordings, is arranged in two subseries. AUDIO TAPES is arranged alphabetically by title of tape as given on original storage boxes.
  Existence and Location of Copies
  Reference copies of sound recordings are filed in the folders.
  Conditions Governing Access
  Boxes 158-161 contain audiovisual material. Restricted fragile. Reference copies may be requested. Consult Access Services for further information.
  - AUDIO TAPES
    Audiovisual material. Restricted fragile. Reference copies may be requested. Consult Access Services for further information.
    - "Biography in Sound --Thornton Wilder" (1 of 2 audiotape reels), 1966 June 4; 1 (Box 158, Item barcode 39002099369168)
    - "Biography in Sound -- Thornton Wilder" (2 of 2 audiotape reels), 1966 June 4; 1 (Box 158, Item barcode 39002099369176)
    - "Edited Wilder Tape", undated; 1 (Box 158, Item barcode 39002099369184)
    - "Harold Mantell Inc. - Wilder 1" (1 of 5 audiotape reels), undated; 1 (Box 158, Item barcode 39002099369192)
    - "Harold Mantell Inc. - Wilder 2" (2 of 5 audiotape reels), undated; 1 (Box 158, Item barcode 39002099369200)
    - "Harold Mantell Inc. - Wilder 3" (3 of 5 audiotape reels), undated; 1 (Box 158, Item barcode 39002099369218)
    - "Harold Mantell Inc. - Wilder 4" (4 of 5 audiotape reels), undated; 1 (Box 158, Item barcode 39002099369226)
    - "Harold Mantell Inc. - Wilder 5" (5 of 5 audiotape reels), undated; 1 (Box 158, Item barcode 39002099369234)
    - "'The MacDowell Colony Story'", acceptance speech by Thornton Wilder, Part I (1 of 2 audiotape reels), 1960 August 13; 1 (Box 159, Item barcode 39002099369242)
    - "'The MacDowell Colony Story'", portion of acceptance speech by Thornton Wilder (2 of 2 audiotape reels), 1960 August 15; 1 (Box 159, Item barcode 39002099369259)
    - "Sketches inspired by 'Our Town'" / "Songs from 'Leaves of Grass' - Wheatlands, Statement for Americans #1" (1 of 2 audiotape reels), 1961 January 20; 1 (Box 159, Item barcode 39002099369267)
      (Tapes possibly of portions of the Inauguration ceremonies for John F. Kennedy?)
    - "Statement for Americans #2" (2 of 2 audiotape reels), 1961 January 20; 1 (Box 159, Item barcode 39002099369275)
      stereo
    - "T.W. on Yale Writing", undated; 1 (Box 159, Item barcode 39002099369283)
    - "T. Wilder, San Luis Rey, 'Ides of March', 'Our Town' / 'Skin'" (1 of 2 audiotape reels), undated; 1 (Box 159, Item barcode 39002099369291)
    - "T. Wilder, San Luis Rey, 'Ides of March', 'Our Town' / 'Skin'" (2 of 2 audiotape reels), undated; 1 (Box 159, Item barcode 39002099369309)
    - "Thornton Wilder", 1951 Aug 6; 1 (Box 159, Item barcode 39002099369317)
      Contents include: portrait of Wilder by Gertrude Stein from Geographic History of America, opening and close of "The Bridge of San Luis Rey", two parts from "The Ides of March", Caesar speaks.
    - "Thornton Wilder", 1951 Aug 6; 1 (Box 160, Item barcode 39002099369150)
      Contents include a scene from "The Emporium", opening and closing scenes from "Our Town, and parts of Act III from "Skin of Our Teeth".
    - "Thornton Wilder Lecture #1 (WYBC-TV)", 1954 June 4-10; 1 (Box 160, Item barcode 39002099369143)
    - "Thornton Wilder program, KCET-TV Ch. 28 L.A.", 1967 November 30; 1 (Box 160, Item barcode 39002099369135)
    - "Thornton Wilder --YMHA 49" (1 of 3 audiotape reels), undated; 1 (Box 161, Item barcode 39002099369325)
    - "Thornton Wilder --YMHA 49" (2 of 3 audiotape reels), undated; 1 (Box 161, Item barcode 39002099369333)
    - "Thornton Wilder -- YMHA 49 tails" (3 of 3 audiotape reels), undated; 1 (Box 161, Item barcode 39002099369341)
    - "Thorton Wilder, tails", Library of Congress Recording Laboratory (1 of 2 audiotape reels), undated; 1 (Box 161, Item barcode 39002099369358)
    - "Thorton Wilder, tails", Library of Congress Recording Laboratory (2 of 2 audiotape reels), undated; 1 (Box 161, Item barcode 39002099369358)
    - [Readings]: "Reading from The Ides of March; Opening and close of Act III of Our Town, Two scenes from The Skin of our Teeth, undated; 1 (Box 161, Item barcode 39002099369366)
    - [Readings]: "Opening and ending of The Bridge of San Luis Rey; interview with T.W. Gertrude Stein Story, tails", undated; 1 (Box 161, Item barcode 39002099369374)
  - SOUND DISCS
    - "Ave Maria--Kurt Schiffler," 1 sound disc, 10,"
    - "Bruce Simonds," 1 sound disc, 12"
    - "Schubert--Thornton Wilder-Kurt Schiffler," 1 sound disc, 12", 1949 May 18
    - "Strauss--Thornton Wilder- Kurt Schiffler," 1 sound disc, 12", 1949 May 18
    - "Thornton Wilder: Biography in Sound," 4 sound discs, 12", 1956 Mar 29
    - "Thornton Wilder: Biography in Sound," 4 sound discs, 12", 1956 Apr 4
- Thornton Wilder Papers Addition, 1911-1974; Series VIII; 0.63; (2 boxes)
  Series VIII, Thornton Wilder Papers Addition, contains correspondence received through members of the Wilder family after the initial processing of the Thornton Wilder Papers. The correspondence is organized by type and then alphabetically by correspondent.
  - FAMILY CORRESPONDENCE
    - Wilder, Amos Niven, 1911-19 (Box 209, Folder 4406-4409)
    - Wilder, Amos Niven, 1926-40 (Box 209, Folder 4410)
    - Wilder, Amos Niven, 1945-70 (Box 209, Folder 4411-4416)
    - Wilder, Amos Niven, 1971, n.d. (Box 209, Folder 4417)
    - Wilder, Amos Parker, 1911, n.d. (Box 209, Folder 4418)
    - Wilder, Charlotte, 1935-39 (Box 209, Folder 4419)
    - Wilder, Charlotte, 1950 (Box 209, Folder 4420-4421)
    - Wilder, Charlotte, 1951 (Box 209, Folder 4422-4423)
    - Wilder, Charlotte, 1952-53 (Box 209, Folder 4424)
    - Wilder, Charlotte, 1956-61 (Box 209, Folder 4425)
    - Wilder, Charlotte, 1962-74 (Box 209, Folder 4426-28)
    - Wilder, Charlotte, n.d. (Box 209, Folder 4429)
    - Wilder, Isabel, 1947, 1962, n.d. (Box 210, Folder 4430-4432)
    - Wilder, Isabel Niven, 1920-45, n.d. (Box 210, Folder 4433)
  - OTHER CORRESPONDENCE
    - Luhan, Mabel Dodge, 1938 Jul 17 (Box 210, Folder 4434)
- Oversize, 48.93; (40 boxes)
  - Hello Dolly program (in Series II), n.d. (Box 162, Folder 3869)
  - Proofs for illustrations of The Bridge of San Luis Rey, 2p (in Series II), n.d. (Box 162, Folder 3870)
  - Galley for The Cabala, with corrections, 1p (in Series II), n.d. (Box 162, Folder 3871)
  - Theatre Royal production of The Matchmaker: poster (in Series II), 1954 Aug 16 (Box 162, Folder 3872)
  - Norwegian(?) production of The Matchmaker: poster (in Series II), 1955 (Box 162, Folder 3873)
  - Galley for Harper's article on "A Platform and a Passion or Two," 4p (in Series II), 1957 Oct 24 (Box 162, Folder 3874)
  - Posters for Our Town (in Series II), n.d. (Box 162, Folder 3875)
  - Poster for "The Rape of Lucrece" (in Series II), [1932] (Box 162, Folder 3875a)
  - Northwestern University: diploma, 1951 Dec (Box 162, Folder 3876)
  - (in Series III)
  - Yale University: diploma, 1947 Jun 14 (Box 162, Folder 3877)
  - (in Series III)
  - Brandeis University Creative Arts Award: certificate (Series III), [1960] (Box 162, Folder 3878)
  - Fridenpreises des Deutschen Buchhandels: Certificate and case (in Series III), 1957 Oct 6 (Box 162, Folder 3879)
  - American Educational Theatre Association: citation (in Series III), 1968 Aug (Box 162, Folder 3880)
  - Order of the British Empire: certificate (in Series III), 1945 Jul 24 (Box 162, Folder 3881)
  - Washington Board of Trade: certificate of award (in Series III), 1957 Mar 4 (Box 162, Folder 3882)
  - New Haven Register article on TNW: Connecticut Resident of the Year 1968 (in Series IV), 1969 Jan 5 (Box 163, Folder 3883)
  - Saturday Review (Cover only, with picture of TNW) (in Series IV), 1935 Apr 6 (Box 163, Folder 3884)
  - New York Times: brief mention of TNW, 1942 Nov 29 (Box 163, Folder 3885)
  - (in Series IV)
  - Herald Tribune - Books: brief mention of TNW (in Series IV), 1962 Oct 28 (Box 163, Folder 3886)
  - New Haven Register: brief mention of TNW (in Series IV), 1970 Jun 15 (Box 163, Folder 3887)
  - New York Times: brief mention of TNW, (in Series IV) (Box 163, Folder 3888)
  - Hartford Courant: Feature story on TNW (in Series IV), 1928 Feb 26 (Box 163, Folder 3889)
  - Yale Daily News: Interview with TNW, (in Series IV) (Box 163, Folder 3890)
  - Die Zeit: Article on TNW (in Series IV), 1957 Nov 14 (Box 163, Folder 3891)
  - New York Herald Tribune: Article on TNW (in Series IV), 1962 May 6 (Box 163, Folder 3892)
  - Vineyard Gazette: Article on TNW (in Series IV), 1966 (Box 163, Folder 3893)
  - Island Reporter: Interview with TNW, (in Series IV) (Box 163, Folder 3894)
  - De Marco, Leonardo: Article on TNW in unknown Italian newspaper, n.d. (Box 163, Folder 3895)
  - (in Series IV)
  - New York Journal: Article on Col. Harold E. Hartney (in Series IV), 1938 Mar 20 (Box 163, Folder 3896)
  - New York Variety: Article on 1937-38 theatre season (in Series IV), 1938 Jun 1 (Box 163, Folder 3897)
  - New York Herarld Tribune: Front page of theatre section (in Series IV), 1939 Nov 12 (Box 163, Folder 3898)
  - Saturday Evening Post: Article on fiction plagiarism (in Series IV), 1943 May 1 (Box 163, Folder 3899)
  - Observer: Book reviews (in Series IV), 1945 Nov 4 (Box 163, Folder 3900)
  - Le Figaro: Article on 'the pursuit of happiness' (in Series IV), 1956 (Box 163, Folder 3901)
    With a paragraph on French stereotypes of American children highlighted
  - New York Times: Article on Swiss ski resort (in Series IV), 1959 Feb 22 (Box 163, Folder 3902)
  - Cronaca di Firenze: One page, unclear which article was of interest to TNW (in Series IV), 1960 Oct 12 (Box 163, Folder 3903)
  - New York Post: Five columns by Leonard Lyons, no evident relation to TNW (in Series IV), 1963 Mar 4-8 (Box 163, Folder 3904)
  - New York Post: Article on Cheryl Crawford (in Series IV), 1964 Sep 1 (Box 163, Folder 3905)
  - The Observer: Review of John Osborne's A Bond Honoured (in Series IV), 1966 Jun 12 (Box 163, Folder 3906)
  - New York Review: Review of a Coleridge anthology edited by William Empson ("See Empson") (in Series IV), 1973 Jun 14 (Box 163, Folder 3907)
  - Unknown French newspaper: Article on the death of Roger Martin du Gard, annotated by TNW (in Series IV) (Box 163, Folder 3908)
  - Unknown Tucson, AZ newspaper: Article on folk band the Ash Alley Singers (in Series IV) (Box 163, Folder 3909)
    Annotated by TNW "This is the girl I am annoying with my attentions"
  - Life magazine: Article on Our Town (in Series IV), 1962 Sep 7 (Box 163, Folder 3910)
  - Life magazine: Cover story on Hello Dolly (in Series IV), 1964 Apr 3 (Box 163, Folder 3911)
  - Life magazine: Cover story on Hello Dolly in Vietnam (in Series IV), 1965 Oct 22 (Box 163, Folder 3912)
  - Life magazine: Cover story on Pearl Bailey in Hello Dolly (in Series IV), 1967 Dec 8 (Box 163, Folder 3913)
  - New York Times Book Review: Review of The Eighth Day (in Series IV), 1967 Apr (Box 163, Folder 3914)
  - New York Times Book Review: Brief mention of The Eighth Day (in Series IV), 1969 Feb 16 (Box 163, Folder 3915)
  - New York Times Book Review (in Series IV), 1973 May 6 (Box 163, Folder 3916)
  - This Week: Article on Our Town (in Series IV), 1969 Nov 8 (Box 163, Folder 3917)
  - Yale graduation picture (in Series V), 1920 (Box 164, Folder 3918)
  - Studio portrait by Harris and Ewing (in Series V), [1922] (Box 164, Folder 3919-3920)
  - Danford Barney portrait (in Series V), 1920s (Box 164, Folder 3921)